NATALIE E. BULGER

Detailed-oriented and driven applicant with 2+ years working in a healthcare field. Experience with Javascript (including Node.js, Express.js, ReactJS), HTML, and CSS. Love problem solving and a strong desire to learn more features of web development.

bulgern20@gmail.com (206) 743 – 4712 Kirkland, WA

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/natalie-bulger-6467b4b0/

Github: https://github.com/nbulger1

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Link to Portfolio: https://nbulger1.github.io/bulgern-portfolio/

Ben's Diner | UW Coding Bootcamp

Languages & Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars.js, MySQL, Sequelize ORM, MVC paradigm, bcrypt, Express-session, Dotenv, Connect-session-sequelize, QR Code API

- Purpose: Create a pandemic conscious restaurant ordering service by allowing users to browse a digital menu and place orders online
- Role & Responsibilities: Creating routes within the MVC paradigm to accept fetch calls from frontend Javascript, assisting group member with Handlebars.js and creating model associations within the sequelize ORM

Deployed URL: https://bens-diner.herokuapp.com/ | Github Repository: https://github.com/wonjong2/Bens Diner.git

My Recipes | UW Coding Bootcamp

Languages & Technologies: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Local Storage, DOM Manipulation, Server-Side APIs (Edamam)

- Purpose: Create an application that pulls from the Edamam API to allow users to search for and save recipes that fit certain criteria (i.e. food restrictions)
- Role & Responsibilities: Utilize front-end Javascript for DOM manipulation as the user interactions with the web page and create local storage handling so the user can save their recipes

URL: https://nbulger1.github.io/my-recipes/ | Github Repository: https://github.com/nbulger1/my-recipes.git

Team Profile Generator | UW Coding Bootcamp

Languages & Technologies: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node.js, Jest, Inquirer

- Purpose: Create a command-line application that takes information, provided by a user, about a software engineering team and generates an HTML webpage with a summary on each person. I was also tasked to write tests for different parts of my code to help make the code maintainable in the future
- Role & Responsibilities: Create the entire application from scratch including the front end display that is created through inquirer as well as write out the tests to ensure the methods on the models were functioning appropriately

Walkthrough Video URL: https://youtu.be/5rVo6Y9TCOY | Github Repository: https://github.com/nbulger1/team-profile-generator.git

Code Quiz | UW Coding Bootcamp

Languages & Technologies: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Local Storage, DOM Manipulation, web-based APIs

- Purpose: Create a five question quiz that must be completed in a certain amount of time and creates a leaderboard of scores so the user can compare their score to their friends
- Role & Responsibilities: Created the entire application from scratch including the entire front-end design with HTML and CSS as well as front-end Javascript for DOM manipulation and local storage handling.

URL: https://nbulger1.github.io/code-quiz/ | Github Repository: https://github.com/nbulger1/code-quiz.git

Weather Dashboard | UW Coding Bootcamp

Languages & Technologies: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Local Storage, DOM Manipulation, Server-Side APIs (openweather.com)

- Purpose: Create a dashboard that pulls from openweather.com and displays the current weather as well as a five-day forecast and allows the user to save the result when a user searches for a city
- Role & Responsibilities: Created the entire application from scratch including the entire front-end design as well as the front-end Javascript to make fetch calls to the API, display the received data through DOM manipulation, and save cities via local storage

URL: https://nbulger1.github.io/weather-dashboard/ | Github Repository: https://github.com/nbulger1/weather-dashboard.git

RELEVANT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ORANGETHEORY FITNESS - MERCER ISLAND, WA

Head Fitness Coach January 2022 – Current

Fitness Coach

- Managing a team of six fitness coaches
- Instruct group fitness classes (Up to 42 people)
- Facilitating continuing education through workshops and all-staff meetings
- Creating class schedules & evaluating coach performance
- Ensuring equipment is functioning appropriately

HARBORVIEW MEDICAL CENTER & SEATTLE FIRE MEDIC ONE - SEATTLE, WA

Research Coordinator

Research Assistant

August 2020 - June 2021

June 2018 - August 2020

- Work on a plethora of research projects primarily involving airway management, end-tidal carbon dioxide, out-of-hospital cardiac
- Work with a variety of softwares including: REDCap, STATA, ORCA, CODESTAT, ESO, and CAD (computer aided dispatch)
- Presented ongoing research at national conferences
- Completed IRB requests, research grants, and research manuscripts
- Manage and schedule current research assistants and maintain a record of the status of current research projects

NORTHWEST AMBULANCE - EVERETT, WA

Emergency Medical Technician

June 2019 – June 2020

- Work on both 911 and interfacility rigs to transport an average of 4-5 Basic Life Support patients per shift
- Perform patient assessments, take basic vital signs, and participate in a two provider team during each shift
- Interact with nurses, physicians, firefighters, and paramedics during every shift

HARBORVIEW INJURY PREVENTION & RESEARCH CENTER - SEATTLE, WA

Intern Research Assistant

June 2017 – August 2017

- Conducted an independent project on the Trauma Patient Transfer Process at Harborview under the guidance of a physician mentor
- Assisted on an ongoing research project at Seattle Children's Hospital for the presence of safe firearm storage in households
- Worked with the Dedoose software for qualitative research projects

HARBORVIEW MEDICAL CENTER DEPARTMENT OF TRAUMA SURGERY - SEATTLE, WA

Volunteer Research Assistant

June 2016 – December 2016

- Assisted with sample collection and processing as well data entry for a randomized clinical trial for dosage delivery of tranexamic acid (TXA) in the prehospital setting, by Seattle Fire intensive care paramedics, for traumatic brain injuries
- Used many wet lab techniques, including micro-pipetting, centrifuging, working in a fume hood, and use of a TEG apparatus
- Follow a multi-step protocol in a wet lab research setting

TECHNICAL SKILLS | CERTIFICATIONS | PUBLICATIONS

- **Web Development**: Javascript, HTML, CSS, web-based APIs, server-side APIs, Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars.js, MySQL, Sequelize ORM, MVC paradigm, ReactJS
- Research Software: Tableau, STATA, REDCap, CODESTAT, ESO, CAD (computer aided dispatch), Dedoose, ORCA, IRB
- Certifications: NREMT, Stop the Bleed Instructor, NASM CPT, CITI Training, OTFit, CPR/AED

Select Publications

- **Bulger N.,** et al. (2021, September). *Prehospital End Tidal Carbon Dioxide Predicts Hemorrhagic Shock Upon Emergency Department Arrival.* Manuscript published in the *Journal of Trauma*.
- Murphy D, Bulger N et al. (2021, July). Fewer Tracheal Intubation Attempts are Associated with Improved Neurologically Intact Survival Following Out-of-Hospital Cardiac Arrest. Manuscript published in Resuscitation.

EDUCATION

CARLETON COLLEGE, Northfield, MN: B.A. in Chemistry

Graduated: March 17th, 2019

HOFSTRA UNIVERSITY, Hempstead, NY: M.S. in Sports Science

Graduated: June 29th, 2021 - GPA: 4.0

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON, Seattle, WA: Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

Anticipated: August 13th, 2022 - Grade (so far): A+